RG 041:003, Connecticut Siting Council
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Siting Council records
1973-1992
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Siting Council
15 cubic feet
The Connecticut Siting Council has jurisdiction over the siting of power facilities, transmission lines, hazardous waste facilities and various other forms of infrastructure including telecommunications sites.
RG041_003
1995-036
Historical Note
The Connecticut Siting Council was first established as the Power Facility Evaluation Council in 1972 following the passage of the Public Utility Environmental Standards Act. In 1981, it became known as the Connecticut Siting Council with the passage of PA 81-369, which expanded the Council’s original jurisdiction over the siting of power facilities and transmission lines to include hazardous waste facilities. The Council’s jurisdiction has since been extended to include various other forms of infrastructure including telecommunications sites.
Source: Connecticut Siting Council website, "About Us" page at http://www.ct.gov/csc/cwp/view.asp?a=895&q=248310 (viewed January 13, 2010).
See also the.
Scope and Content
There is currently only one series of hearing transcripts, 1973-1992.
Arrangement
Series 1. Hearing transcripts, 1973-1992, are arranged by docket number.
Related Material
RG 041:002, Public Utilities Commission, 1911-1988, bulk 1911-1976
RG 041:004, Public Utlities Control Authority, 1975-1976
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut Siting Council; Connecticut. Power Facility Evaluation Council
Subjects:
Administrative agencies -- Public meetings -- Connecticut; Electric lines -- Environmental aspects -- Connecticut; Electric power transmission -- Environmental aspects -- Connecticut; Cellular telephone systems -- Environmental aspects -- Connecticut; Radio and television towers -- Environmental aspects -- Connecticut; Wireless communication systems -- Environmental aspects -- Connecticut; Mobile communication systems -- Environmental aspects -- Connecticut; Power-plants -- Environmental aspects -- Connecticut; Hydroelectric power plants -- Environmental aspects -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Correspondence; Transcripts
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 1. Hearing Transcripts, 1973-1992
  - Docket No. 1B, Application on behalf of the Connecticut Light and Power Company for a second amendment to the certificate of environmental compatibility and public need issued to the Northeast Utilities Service Company on January 31, 1973 in connection with its proposed 115 kV electric transmission line between Branford and Old Saybrook, Connecticut, 1975 March 11, 13; April 2, 7; May 12 (Box 1)
    There are two transcripts for April 2, 1975 because there were two sessions that day.
    There are two copies of the May 12, 1975 transcript.
  - Docket No. 2, Application of the Connecticut Light and Power Company...for a 115 kV transmission line between points in the towns of Redding and Ridgefield, 1973 March 28 (Box 1)
  - Docket No. 4, Application by the Millstone Point Company...for an electric generating facility with a nominal net electrical capability of 1150mw, identified as "Millstone Nuclear Power Station Unit No. 3" located in the town of Waterford, Connecticut, 1973 September 24, 25, 26, 27, 28; October 1, 5, 15, 16, 19 (Box 1)
  - Docket No. 5, Application of the Connecticut Light and Power Company...for electric transmission lines between New Milford and Bethel, 1974 July 8, 11, 12, 15; July 16, 17, 23, 24, 25, 30, 31; August 1; 1975 January 20 (Box 2)
    There are two copies of the January 20, 1975 transcript.
  - Docket No. 7, Application on behalf of the Connecticut Light & Power Company...with respect to a proposed new kV transmission line along a route through the towns of Mansfield, Willington & Stafford, with an alternate route through the towns of Vernon, Ellington, Tolland & Stafford, 1975 May 6, 7, 8, 13; June 12 (Box 3)
  - Docket No. 9, Application of the Connecticut Light and Power Company...with respect to a proposed new 345 kV transmission between Oxbow Junction, Haddam and Black Pond Junction, Meriden, and the rebuilding of a 115 kV transmission line between Beseck Junction, Wallingford and East Meriden Substation in Meriden, 1976 August 30, 31; September 8, 13, 14, 21, 27 (Box 3)
  - Docket No. 10, Application of the Hartford Electric Light Company...with respect to the reconstruction under the Connecticut River of an existing overhead 115 kV electric transmission line and two existing overhead 345 kV electric transmission lines crossing the river between the Town of Middletown and East Hampton at a location known as Scovill Rock near the Haddam town line, 1976 November 4; 1981 January 6 (Box 3)
    There are two copies of the November 4, 1976 transcript.
    The January 6, 1981 transcript is titled: A hearing concerning the application of Northeast Utilities...with respect to the reconstruction of transmission lines at Scovill Rock crossing the Connecticut River.
  - Docket No. 11, Application of the Hartford Electric Light Company...for electric transmission lines along a route in the towns of Manchester, South Windsor, Windsor, and Bloomfield, with a partial alternative route running through a portion of East Hartford, 1977 July 19, 20, 21, 27 (Box 3)
    There are two transcripts for July 20, 1977 because there were two sessions that day.
  - Docket No. 12, Application of the Hartford Electric Light Company and the Connecticut Light and Power Company...with respect to the construction of a proposed new overhead electric 345 kV transmission line along the route of existing right of way extending approximately 47 miles from the Millstone generating station, in Waterford, through the towns of Waterford, Montville, Bozrah, Franklin, Lebanon, Columbia, Andover, Hebron, Glastonbury and Manchester to the Manchester substation, 1977 November 29, 30 (Box 4)
  - Docket No. 13, A hearing conducted for the purpose of taking evidence with respect to a proposed telecommunication tower to be constructed in Bethel, Connecticut, 1978 January 31; February 1, 6, 23; March 6, 7, 10, 29; April 6 (Box 4)
    There are two transcripts for January 31, February 1, March 7, 10 because there were two sessions those days.
    There are three transcripts for February 23, March 6, because there were three sessions those days.
  - Docket No. 14, A hearing for the purpose of taking evidence concerning the application of the Housatonic Cable Vision Company...with respect to the construction of a proposed community antenna television tower to be constructed in Newtown, Connecticut, 1978 November 14 (Box 4)
    There are two transcripts because there were two sessions.
  - Docket No. 15, Application by Housatonic Cable Vision Company...respecting a proposed community antenna television tower be constructed in Monroe, Connecticut, 1979 February 20 (Box 4)
    There are two copies of this transcript.
  - Docket No. 16, A public hearing concerning the application of the Greater Hartford CATV, Inc.,...for television tower in Glastonbury, Connecticut, 1979 November 27 (Box 4)
  - Docket No. 17, A hearing concerning the application of AMTRAK...with respect to the construction of a 100 foot antenna pole on railroad property in New Haven, Connecticut, 1980 April 30 (Box 4)
  - Docket No. 18, A hearing concerning the application of Northwest Cablevision, Inc....to erect a VHF troposcatter parabolic reflector in the town of Winsted, Connecticut, 1980 June 3 (Box 4)
  - Docket No. 19, A hearing concerning the application of Northeast Utilities...with respect to the reconstruction of transmission lines at Scovill Rock crossing the Connecticut River, 1981 January 6, 7, 8, 13, 23, 26; March 18, 20; April 12, 13, 15, 19, 26, 28; May 3, 5 (Box 5)
    The transcripts for March 18 and May 5 are in two parts.
  - Docket No. 22, A hearing on the application of the Department of Environmental Protection with respect to construction of a 120 foot microwave tower at John Tom Hill, Glastonbury, Connecticut, 1981 February 11 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 23, A public hearing with respect to the revision to the telecommunication tower located at Connecticut Transit property on 470 James Street, New Haven, Connecticut owned by the State of Connecticut, 1981 April 15 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 23, A public hearing with respect to the revision to the telecommunication tower located at Connecticut Transit property on 53 Vernon Street, Hartford, Connecticut, owned by the State of Connecticut, 1981 April 15 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 24, D.E.P. application for certificate of a sixty-foot microwave tower, 1981 September 17 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 25, Application of the Connecticut Light and Power Company and the Hartford Electric Light Company...for the construction of an overhead transmission line along a route through the towns of Waterford, Montville, Bozrah, Franklin, Lebanon, Columbia, Andover, Hebron, Glastonbury and Manchester, 1982 January 11 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 26, An application...respect to the reconstruction of an existing overhead 115kV electric transmission line extending approximately 9.3 miles between Plumtree Substation, in Bethel, and Ridgefield Junction, in Redding, 1982 June 14, 15 (Box 6)
    Also includes corrected transcript pages.
  - Docket No. 27, Application of the United Illuminating Company...for the modification of Bridgeport Harbor Unit No. 3 to burn either low-sulfur coal or oil, 1982 August 17; September 17 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 28, Application of Storer Communications of Clinton, Inc., to erect a community antenna television tower in the town of Haddam, 1982 August 16 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 29, Application of Cablevision of Connecticut...for certain community antenna television equipment, 1982 September 16 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 30, Application for construction of a community television tower at Plain Hill Road in Norwich, 1982 September 13 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 31, Application of Valley Cable Vision, Inc...for a modification to its existing CATV tower, 1982 September 23 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 32, Application of the Metropolitan District...for the Goodwin and Colebrook hydroelectric power plants, 1983 May 18 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 33, Application of United Cablevision Corp. of eastern Connecticut..., 1983 June 8 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 34, Public hearing on the application of Continental Cablevision of Connecticut, Inc....for the erection of a community antenna tower, 1983 August 18 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 35. An application submitted by Southern New England Telephone Company...for the construction, maintenance and operation of four facilities, each of which include a telecommunications tower and associated equipment building, in the towns of Hartford, East Hartford, South Windsor, and Southington, Connecticut, to provide domestic cellular radio telecommunication service, 1983 September 29, 30 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 37, Application of Community Television Cable Systems, Inc., d/b/a Rollins Cablevision of Connecticut...for a five-meter earth station receiver in the town of North Branford, Connecticut, 1984 January 9 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 38, An application submitted by Continental Cablevision Company of Connecticut, Incorporated...for the erection of a community antenna television tower in the town of Enfield, 1984 January 25 (Box 6)
  - Docket No. 40, Application of SNET...for the construction, maintenance and operation of facilities to provide cellular service in Hartford and Middlesex Counties, 1984 March 21, 22 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 41, Application of Continental Cablevision of Connecticut, Inc....for the erection of a community antenna television tower in the town of Windsor Locks, 1984 April 4 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 42, Application of Hartford CATV, Inc....for the erection of a community antenna television tower in the town of West Hartford, 1984 April 25 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 43, Application of Tele-Media Company of Northeastern Connecticut...for the erection of community antennae television towers and associated equipment in the towns of Ashford, Lebanon, Mansfield, Woodstock and Canterbury, Connecticut, 1984 May 2, 9 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 44, Application of S.N.E.T. Co....for the construction, maintenance and operation of facilities to provide cellular service in Branford, Guilford, Milford, North Haven, Waterbury and Woodbridge, Connecticut, 1984 June 11 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 45, Application of SNETCO...for the construction, maintenance, and operation of facilities to provide cellular service in Fairfield County, 1984 June 19, 20; August 14 (Box 7)
    There are two transcripts for June 20 because there were two sessions.
  - Docket No. 46, Application submitted by the Connecticut Resources Recovery Authority, the Metropolitan District, and the Connecticut Light and Power Company...for the construction of a solid waste processing facility, reconstruction of a power block (steam generating) facility, and refurbishment of the South Meadow electric generating station, 1984 November 7, 9 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 46A, Application of the Connecticut Light and Power Company for an amendment to the certificate of environmental compatibility and public need issued in Docket No. 46, 1985 April 9, 18 (Box 7)
    Includes transmittal correspondence.
  - Docket No. 47, An application submitted by Community TV Systems, Inc., d/b/a Rollins Cablevision of Connecticut...for the construction of a microwave hub site tower and associated equipment in the town of Guilford, Connecticut, 1985 March 6 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 48, Application of United Illuminating Co....for the construction, maintenance, and operation of an electric transmission line in the city of Bridgeport, Connecticut, 1985 July 8 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 49, An application of the Connecticut Resources Authority...for the construction, maintenance, and operation of an electric generating facility in the city of Bridgeport, 1985 May 28 (Box 7)
    Includes letter concerning typographical error.
  - Docket No. 50, The application of the New York SMSA Limited Partnership...for the construction, maintenance, and operation of a facility in the town of Greenwich, Connecticut to provide cellular service, 1985 May 22 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 51, An application submitted by Southern New England Telephone Company...for the construction, and maintenance, and operation of facilities to provide cellular service in Hartford and Middlesex Counties, 1985 August 7, 12 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 52, The application of Ogden Martin Systems, Inc., 1985 July 29 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 53, Application of Tele-Media of Northeastern Connecticut...for the erection of community antenna towers and associated equipment in the towns of Brooklyn and Thompson, Connecticut, 1985 September 4 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 54, Application of O'Brien Energy Systems, Inc....to construct a cogeneration facility in the city of Hartford, Connecticut, 1986 January 6 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 54A, Request for amendment to the certificate of environmental compatibility and public need issued by the Connecticut Siting Council, 1987 December 16 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 55, Joint application of United cable Television Services Corp. and United Cable Television Corp. of Connecticut...to establish a community antenna television head-end facility in the town of Farmington, Connecticut, 1985 December 4, 12, 30 (Box 7)
  - Docket No. 56, Application of Metro Mobile CTS of New Haven, Inc....for the construction, maintenance and operation of facilities to provide cellular services in New Haven County, 1986 January 15; February 6, 20; March 13 (Box 8)
    There are two transcripts for January 15 and March 13 because there were two sessions.
    One of the transcripts from January 15 states 1985.
  - Docket No. 56A, Public hearing on the Council's amendment resolution regarding the decision in Docket 56, 1986 July 10 (Box 8)
  - Docket No. 56B, An application for an amendment to the certificate of environmental compatibility and public need issued in Docket 56 to Metro Mobile CTS of New Haven, Inc., for telecommunications towers and associated equipment to provide cellular service in New Haven County. Relocation of Naugatuck site, 1987 May 20 (Box 8)
  - Docket No. 57, Application of the Connecticut Light and Power Company...for reconstruction of a 115 kV electric transmission line between Trumbull Junction in Trumbull and Old Town Substation in Bridgeport, 1986 February 25 (Box 8)
  - Docket No. 58, An application of Hartford Cellular Co....for the construction, maintenance, and operation of facilities to provide cellular service in Hartford, Tolland and Middlesex Counties, 1986 March 18; April 15, 17; May 21 (Box 8)
  - Docket No. 59, An application for Capitol District Energy Center Cogeneration Associates...for the construction, maintenance, and operation of a 55 MW cogeneration facility in Hartford, Connecticut, 1986 March 20; May 28 (Box 8)
  - Docket No. 60, An application submitted by Flagg Energy Development Corporation...for the construction, maintenance, and operation of a 10,000 KW cogeneration facility located in Hartford, Connecticut, 1986 April 3 (Box 8)
  - Docket No. 61, Application of Applied Energy services, Inc....for construction, maintenance and operation of the Thames Cogeneration Plant located in the town of Montville, Connecticut, 1986 June 11; July 29; August 7 (Box 8)
  - Docket No. 62, An application of the Southern New England Telephone Company...for the construction, maintenance, and operation of facilities to provide cellular service in the town of Canton, Connecticut, 1986 May 15; June 6, 16 (Box 8)
  - Docket No. 63, An application of the Department of Environmental Protection...for the construction of microwave telecommunication towers in the towns of Glastonbury and Montville, Connecticut, 1986 June 9 (Box 9)
  - Docket No. 64, Application of Dexter Corporation...for the construction, maintenance, and operation of a 52 MW cogeneration facility located in Windsor Locks, Connecticut, 1986 September 29 (Box 9)
  - Docket No. 65, Application of Cablevision Systems of Southern Connecticut, Limited Partnership...for the erection of a community antenna television tower in the city of Bridgeport, Connecticut, 1986 September 17 (Box 9)
  - Application submitted to the Council by Cablevision of Connecticut, Limited Partnership...to construct a community antenna television head-end facility in Easton, Connecticut, 1986 October 1 (Box 9)
  - Docket No. 67, Application of the Southern new England Telephone Company...for the construction, maintenance, and operation of facilities to provide cellular service in the towns of East Lyme and Waterford, Connecticut, 1986 October 15 (Box 9)
  - Docket No. 69, Application of Metro Mobile CTS of Hartford, Inc....for the construction, maintenance, and operation of facilities to provide cellular service in the towns of Killingworth, Middletown, and Old Saybrook, Connecticut, 1986 November 3, 18; December 9. 18 (Box 9)
  - Docket No. 71, Application of Connecticut Resources Recovery Authority, Midstate Regional Resource Recovery Authority, and American REF-FUEL Company...for the Midstate regional Resource Recovery facility would generate electricity by mass-burning municipal solid waste in the city of Middletown, Connecticut, 1986 October 27 (Box 9)
  - Docket No. 73, Application of Metro Mobile CTS of Fairfield County, Inc....for the construction, maintenance, and operation of facilities to provide cellular service in the town of Greenwich and in the cities of Norwalk and Stamford, Connecticut, 1987 February 26 (Box 9)
  - Docket No. 74, Application of Connecticut Resources Recovery Authority, Southeastern Regional Resources Recovery Authority, and American REF-FUEL Company...for the Southeastern Connecticut Regional Resource Recovery facility, 1987 January 29; March 5; May 7, 12, 18, 21, 26, 27; June 4, 8, 9 (Box 9-10)
    There are two transcripts for March 5 and May 21 because there were two sessions those days.
    The transcript for June 4 is in two parts.
  - Docket No. 75, An application of the Southern New England Telephone Company...for the construction, maintenance and operation of two facilities to expand cellular service in Fairfield County, 1987 March 12 (Box 10)
  - Docket No. 76, Application of Century Cable Management Corporation...for the construction of a community antenna television tower in the town of East Haddam, Connecticut, 1987 June 3 (Box 10)
  - Docket No. 77, An application of Metro Mobile CTS of Fairfield County, Inc....for cellular telephone antennas and associated equipment in the town of Trumbull, Connecticut, 1987 June 17 (Box 10)
  - Docket No. 79, An application of Metro Mobile CTS of Fairfield County, Inc....for a cellular telephone facility in the city of Danbury, Connecticut, 1987 August 10 (Box 10)
  - Docket No. 82, Application of Connecticut Light & Power Company...for a 115-kV underground transmission line to Connecticut the Capitol District Energy Center Cogeneration Project tot he existing 115-kV Northwest-Hartford-Southwest Hartford transmission line in Hartford, Connecticut, 1987 September 21 (Box 10)
  - Docket No. 83, AES-Thames cogeneration plant, 1987 November 9 (Box 10)
  - Docket No. 84, Application of SNET Cellular, Inc....for a cellular telephone antenna tower and associated equipment in the town of Haddam, Connecticut, 1987 December 2 (Box 10)
  - Docket No. 86, Application of Metro Mobile CTS of Fairfield County, Inc., 1987 December 14, 21 (Box 10)
  - Docket No. 87, Application of SNET Cellular, Inc...for a cellular telephone antenna tower and associated equipment in the town of Norwich, Connecticut, 1988 February 8 (Box 10)
  - Docket No. 88, An application of Metro Mobile CTS of New Haven, Inc....for cellular telephone antennas and associated equipment in the town of Southbury, Connecticut, 1988 January 4 (Box 10)
  - Docket No. 89, An application of Metro Mobile CTS of Fairfield County, Inc....for cellular telephone antennas and associated equipment in the town of Newtown, Connecticut, 1988 January 6 (Box 10)
  - Docket No. 90. Application of SNET Cellular, Inc....for a cellular telephone antenna tower and associated equipment in the town of Southbury, Connecticut, 1988 January 11 (Box 10)
  - Docket No. 92HW, Envirite Corporation application... for a certificate of public safety and necessity for modifications to a hazardous waste facility in Thomaston, Connecticut, 1988 May 2, 5 (Box 10)
  - Docket No. 95, An application of the Connecticut Light and Power Company...for the construction of a new substation in the town of Darien, Connecticut, 1988 May 9 (Box 11)
  - Docket No. 96, Application of Killingly Energy Limited Partnership for a facility which would generate electricity from the burning of waste wood..., 1988 September 8, 9; October 6, 20, 21; November 17, 18; December 8 (Box 11)
  - Docket No. 99, Application of Metro Mobile CTS of Fairfield County, Inc., to construct a cellular telephone tower in the city of Stamford, Connecticut..., 1988 October 3, 13; November 10 (Box 11)
  - Docket No. 102, Application of SNET Cellular, Inc....for cellular telephone antennas and associated equipment in the town of Redding, Connecticut..., 1989 February 27; March 9; April 18 (Box 13)
    There are two transcripts for February 27 because there were two sessions.
  - Docket No. 103, Application of Bio-Gen Torrington Partnership...to construct a 15 MW wood-burning electric generating facility in the city of Torrington, Connecticut..., 1989 February 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 28; March 29, 30, 31; April 11, 13; May 17, 18 (Box 12)
  - Docket No. 104, An application of SNET Cellular, Inc....for cellular telephone antenna and associated equipment in the town of Killingworth, Connecticut, 1989 March 7 (Box 13)